<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi, I'm ninelore!</title><link>https://9lo.re/</link><description>Recent content on Hi, I'm ninelore!</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Content: &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;/a> | Code: &lt;a href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.en.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AGPL 3&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 18:20:37 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://9lo.re/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Projects</title><link>https://9lo.re/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 18:20:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://9lo.re/projects/</guid><description>Current Play Arma on Linux Archived Build AndroidAPS in a terminal without Android Studio Broken links?</description></item><item><title>Build AndroidAPS in a terminal</title><link>https://9lo.re/project/aaps-term-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:36:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://9lo.re/project/aaps-term-build/</guid><description>This is a guide on how to build a signed AndroidAPS APK from a terminal (headless) without Android Studio.
A example use case for this would be building AAPS via SSH from your phone if you need a new apk for whatever reason while you have no physical access to your PC.
Note: This Guide is a draft that aims to be integrated into the AAPS Wiki once finished!
Option 1: Prepare Linux / WSL This will build AndroidAPS with either your Linux system or with the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</description></item><item><title>Play Arma on Linux</title><link>https://9lo.re/project/armaonlinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 21:39:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://9lo.re/project/armaonlinux/</guid><description>Preamble A few months and improvements to Proton after its first release, i had the first known, good working Arma installation on Linux.
Since Proton 4.11 as good as all tweaks needed to run Arma became obsolete, and it became as easy as never before to play not only Arma and Steam Games, but also non-Steam games because of many Proton improvements being up streamed to Wine. You can check if your games are working on the Lutris website, the WineHQ and the ProtonDB websites.</description></item><item><title>Blog Cleanup</title><link>https://9lo.re/posts/001-reboot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 19:37:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://9lo.re/posts/001-reboot/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve removed some stuff. The blog will start anew, but dont expect alot of posts.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://9lo.re/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://9lo.re/about/</guid><description>Many know me as ninelore, but my real name is Ingo. This is my personal Blog, and you should treat everything that you read in my blog posts as opinions if not stated otherwise.
Childhood Born in the German State of Hesse, I got my first PC at the age of five, and my first contact with Linux with seven years.
I lived a very rough childhood with, I dare to say, abuse.</description></item></channel></rss>