<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hi, Im ninelore!</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Hi, Im ninelore!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:36:38 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninelore.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Projects</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 18:20:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/projects/</guid><description>Current Play Arma on Linux Build AndroidAPS in a terminal without Android Studio Archived Broken links?</description></item><item><title>Build AndroidAPS in a terminal</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/project/aaps-term-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 16:36:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/project/aaps-term-build/</guid><description>This is a guide on how to build a signed AndroidAPS APK from a terminal (headless) without Android Studio.
A example use case for this would be building AAPS via SSH from your phone if you need a new apk for whatever reason while you have no physical access to your PC.
Note: This Guide is a draft that aims to be integrated into the AAPS Wiki once finished!
Ubuntu Setup apt Deps: Get these packages from your package manager sudo apt install wget git openjdk-8-jre-headless openjdk-11-jre-headless zip unzip zipalign gradle</description></item><item><title>Manjaro Linux' problems</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/004-manjaro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:16:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/004-manjaro/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of Websites that list the problems of Manjaro Linux https://manjarno.snorlax.sh/
https://rentry.co/manjaro-controversies
https://www.hadet.dev/Manjaro-Bad/
https://averagelinuxuser.com/manjaro-review/
Average Manjaro Lines of code For context: Manjaro script do all kinds of things that are highly advised against by the Arch Linux devs 1 2
Oh God (source link)
Please Stop (source link)</description></item><item><title>Lets talk politics (german)</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/003-lets-talk-politics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 18:18:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/003-lets-talk-politics/</guid><description>Ich schreibe diesen Post in meiner Muttersprache, da ich sicher gehen will das ich mich korrekt ausdrücke.
Ihr habt vielleicht irgentwo schon mal gelesen das ich mich als Idealist bezeichne. Es gibt viele Dinge die man ändern könnte um vielen zu helfen. Leider besteht die Politik größtenteils aus Individuen, die den persönlichen Vorteil oder den Vorteil von Großkonzernen suchen, was im Endeffekt allen schadet.
Im Vorfeld der Bundestagswahl 2021 (folgend BTW21 abgekürzt) hat Rezo eine Reihe von Videos veröffentlicht, die die Thematik in deutschen Raum gut erklären und größtenteils auch meine persönliche Meinung widerspiegelt.</description></item><item><title>Why I stopped Using Linux</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/002-why-i-stopped-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/002-why-i-stopped-using-linux/</guid><description>In August 2018 I decided to switch to Linux almost entirely. In this post I will write about my journey with Linux, what experiences I made and why I switched back to windows recently.
The motif I was tired of Windows crashes and the privacy concerns. Also, Windows brings alot of bloat with it that nobody needs.
Last but not least: Windows is flawed in it&amp;rsquo;s own ways, like the occasionally BSOD&amp;rsquo;s or the slow Windows Update.</description></item><item><title>Play Arma on Linux</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/project/armaonlinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 21:39:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/project/armaonlinux/</guid><description>Preamble: A few months and improvements to Proton after its first release, i had the first known, good working Arma installation on Linux.
Since Proton 4.11 as good as all tweaks needed to run Arma became obsolete, and it became as easy as never before to play not only Arma and Steam Games, but also non-Steam games because of many Proton improvements being up streamed to Wine. You can check if your Games are working on the Lutris Website, the WineHQ and the ProtonDB Websites.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to ninelore's Blog</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/001-my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 19:37:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/001-my-first-post/</guid><description>Welcome to my new Blog I decided to make this Blog to write about my thoughs, how random they may be. Possible Topics could be:
experience i made opinions i need to share tutorials whatever else could come in my mind Why i decided to start a Blog It was the recent Post of the Lutris founder Mathieu that ignited an uge inside me that i should share my thoughs.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/about/</guid><description>Many know me as ninelore, but my real name is Ingo. This is my personal Blog, and you should treat everything that you read in my blog posts as opinions if not stated otherwise.
Childhood Born in the German State of Hesse, I got my first PC at the age of five, and my first contact with Linux with seven years.
I lived a very rough childhood with, I dare to say, abuse.</description></item></channel></rss>