<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Hi, Im ninelore!</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Hi, Im ninelore!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CC BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:16:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninelore.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manjaro Linux' problems</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/004-manjaro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 17:16:56 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/004-manjaro/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of Websites that list the problems of Manjaro Linux https://manjarno.snorlax.sh/
https://rentry.co/manjaro-controversies
https://www.hadet.dev/Manjaro-Bad/
https://averagelinuxuser.com/manjaro-review/
Average Manjaro Lines of code For context: Manjaro script do all kinds of things that are highly advised against by the Arch Linux devs 1 2
Oh God (source link)
Please Stop (source link)</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="heres-a-quick-list-of-websites-that-list-the-problems-of-manjaro-linux">Here&rsquo;s a quick list of Websites that list the problems of Manjaro Linux</h3>
<p><a href="https://manjarno.snorlax.sh/">https://manjarno.snorlax.sh/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://rentry.co/manjaro-controversies">https://rentry.co/manjaro-controversies</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.hadet.dev/Manjaro-Bad/">https://www.hadet.dev/Manjaro-Bad/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://averagelinuxuser.com/manjaro-review/">https://averagelinuxuser.com/manjaro-review/</a></p>
<h4 id="average-manjaro-lines-of-code">Average Manjaro Lines of code</h4>
<p>For context: Manjaro script do all kinds of things that are highly advised against by the Arch Linux devs <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/System_maintenance#Avoid_certain_pacman_commands">1</a> <a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/title/System_maintenance#Be_careful_with_unofficial_packages">2</a></p>
<p><a href="https://gitlab.manjaro.org/packages/core/manjaro-system/blob/master/manjaro-update-system.sh#L302">Oh God (source link)</a><br>

    <span class="image ">
        <img src="/pictures/manjarocode.png" alt="" />
    </span>


</p>
<p><a href="https://gitlab.manjaro.org/packages/core/manjaro-system/blob/master/manjaro-update-system.sh#L464">Please Stop (source link)</a><br>

    <span class="image ">
        <img src="/pictures/manjarocode2.png" alt="" />
    </span>


</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Lets talk politics (german)</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/003-lets-talk-politics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 18:18:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/003-lets-talk-politics/</guid><description>Ich schreibe diesen Post in meiner Muttersprache, da ich sicher gehen will das ich mich korrekt ausdrücke.
Ihr habt vielleicht irgentwo schon mal gelesen das ich mich als Idealist bezeichne. Es gibt viele Dinge die man ändern könnte um vielen zu helfen. Leider besteht die Politik größtenteils aus Individuen, die den persönlichen Vorteil oder den Vorteil von Großkonzernen suchen, was im Endeffekt allen schadet.
Im Vorfeld der Bundestagswahl 2021 (folgend BTW21 abgekürzt) hat Rezo eine Reihe von Videos veröffentlicht, die die Thematik in deutschen Raum gut erklären und größtenteils auch meine persönliche Meinung widerspiegelt.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ich schreibe diesen Post in meiner Muttersprache, da ich sicher gehen will das ich mich korrekt ausdrücke.</p>
<p>Ihr habt vielleicht irgentwo schon mal gelesen das ich mich als Idealist bezeichne. Es gibt viele Dinge die man ändern könnte um vielen zu helfen. Leider besteht die Politik größtenteils aus Individuen, die den persönlichen Vorteil oder den Vorteil von Großkonzernen suchen, was im Endeffekt allen schadet.<br>
Im Vorfeld der Bundestagswahl 2021 (folgend BTW21 abgekürzt) hat Rezo eine Reihe von Videos veröffentlicht, die die Thematik in deutschen Raum gut erklären und größtenteils auch meine persönliche Meinung widerspiegelt.</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/rIj3qskDAZM">Rezo: Zerstörung Teil 1: Imkompetenz</a><br>
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ljcz4tA101U">Rezo: Zerstörung Teil 2: Klima-Katastrophe</a><br>
<a href="https://youtu.be/3Ya7pEDndgE">Rezo: Zerstörung Finale: Korruption</a></p>
<p>Ich hatte auf eine Jameika-Koalition gehofft, allerdings ist Ampel immer noch 100 mal besser als eine CDU-Regierung.<br>
Wir können nur hoffen das das Versprochene druchgesetzt wird und die Schande der letzten Regierungen unter der CDU bereinigt werden. Ansonsten müssen wir, alleine wegen dem Klimas, mit der schlimmsten Zukunft rechnen. Denn Deutschland ist mit Abstand Nummer 1 in Klimaemissionen pro Kopf. Das muss sich ändern, und zwar schnell.</p>
<p>Ich hatte letztens eine Debatte mit einem Freund über die Klima-Konferenz COP26 in Glasgow. Er argumentierte das die FFF Proteste sämtliche Corona-Schutzmaßnahmen gebrochen haben und somit viele Menschen gefährdet haben.Er hat zwar recht damit, aber im Nachhinein denke ich das diese Proteste trotzdem richtig waren. Zum einen wegen der Dringlichkeit des von Klimaschutz und die katastrophalen Folgen wenn wir versagen, aber auch wegen einer anderen, zugegebenrmaßen extremeren persönlichen Meinung, über die ich zur Zeit nicht sprechen möchte.</p>
<p>Aber genug von Deutschland. Es gibt genug andere Besorgniserregende Konflikte wie</p>
<ul>
<li>Der erneut aufflammende Russland-Ukraine Komflikt mit dem größtem Truppenaufmarsch seid 2014</li>
<li>Chinas Anspruch auf Taiwan und zahllose Inseln im Südchinesischem Meer, die zu anderen Ländern wie zum Beispiel den Phillipinen angehören<br>
Diese Brennpunkte haben das Potential jederzeit zu blutigen Kriegen zu werden, was mir echt Angst macht.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ich könnte noch viel mehr Schreiben, aber mir fehlt im Moment die Zeit. Rechnet mit mehr Posts zum Thema.<br>
Auch könnt ihr mehr Blog Aktivität in nächster Zeit erwarten ;)</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Why I stopped Using Linux</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/002-why-i-stopped-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/002-why-i-stopped-using-linux/</guid><description>In August 2018 I decided to switch to Linux almost entirely. In this post I will write about my journey with Linux, what experiences I made and why I switched back to windows recently.
The motif I was tired of Windows crashes and the privacy concerns. Also, Windows brings alot of bloat with it that nobody needs.
Last but not least: Windows is flawed in it&amp;rsquo;s own ways, like the occasionally BSOD&amp;rsquo;s or the slow Windows Update.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In August 2018 I decided to switch to Linux almost entirely. In this post I will write about my journey with Linux, what experiences I made and why I switched back to windows recently.</p>
<h1 id="the-motif">The motif</h1>
<p>I was tired of Windows crashes and the privacy concerns. Also, Windows brings alot of bloat with it that nobody needs.<br>
Last but not least: Windows is flawed in it&rsquo;s own ways, like the occasionally BSOD&rsquo;s or the slow Windows Update.</p>
<p>There are several reasons to go for Linux. But that&rsquo;s another topic.</p>
<h1 id="the-time">The Time</h1>
<h3 id="the-beginning">The Beginning</h3>
<p>I had my very first contact with Linux in 2007 with Ubuntu 7.04, after seeing it used by a barkeeper I know. In the time between this and 2018 I only experimented with Linux in VM&rsquo;s because it&rsquo;s use was very limited in my youth. But in August of 2018 I made the jump into the cold water and didn&rsquo;t regret it. I was using Kubuntu for a very short time before getting into and mastering Arch Linux very quickly.</p>
<p>I got a lot of Games working pretty quickly, among them are for example &ldquo;World of Warcraft&rdquo;, &ldquo;Squad&rdquo; and &ldquo;Elite: Dangerous&rdquo;. I also got very quickly used to termainal workflow with vim, git, the file manager ranger and others.</p>
<p>In Feburary of 2019 was I able to play Arma on Linux for the first time. From then on <a href="https://discord.gg/p28Ra36">ArmaOnUnix</a> and I made almost always new improvements.</p>
<h3 id="my-time-with-linux-in-general">My time with Linux in general</h3>
<p>With the time passed I developed a lot of things, mainly quality of life scripts. Early on I used KDE Plasma as my Desktop enviroment, before I experimented with several tiling window managers. I used i3 mainly up until mid-2020, where I had enough free time and boredom to get into Lua and the Awesome window manager. I began quickly to like Awesome and used it as my main window manager from then on. <a href="https://github.com/ninelore/dotfiles">You can find my dotfiles here.</a></p>
<h3 id="moving-back-to-windows">Moving back to Windows</h3>
<p>In Feburary 2021 I got a new laptop with hybrid graphics. Also my private situation changed and I was looking to get a more stable system thats working without much tinkering. I tried very hard to stay with Linux, but in the end there were two factors that forced me to go back:</p>
<ul>
<li>There were several Problems related to Optimus, mainly with the AMD iGPU, and driver problems with the new Renoir iGPU itself.</li>
<li>Several pieces of software I now require are not available on Linux and have no alternative that compliment my needs.</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t have the time nor the storage space to make a dual-boot system</li>
</ul>
<p>After some weeks, I am now a fan of WSL, because it helps me to develope and use my previously started projects like <a href="https://ninelore.github.io/projects/#arma-on-linux">Arma on Linux</a></p>
<h1 id="the-conclusion">The Conclusion</h1>
<p><em>Note: This may or may not be very similar to a blogpost of Matthieu Commandon, the founder of Lutris. This is because i agree with most of its statements and opinions</em></p>
<p>Recently I realized that the Micorsoft hatred gets overvalued. Microsoft is no longer in Position to stop FOSS, like they tried with the Haloween documents and the EEE stategy. The hate on Windows was fun as a meme for a long while, but I now see far worse threats to online privacy and the freedom now.</p>
<p>When i thought about it, there is no reason to question the validity of the work of teams who ship operation systems. Its a important platform to build ontop of. Big open source projects would be in deep ship if nobody would lead the Project with governance. Open sourcing is not the solution for every project. Desktop Linux misses a stable foundation and some things may break at any given point in time. There are also problems within the Linux community, like fanboying implementation X, accusing of using &ldquo;unholy&rdquo; technical choices or treating bugtrackers like their Amazon wishlists. Because of latter, i think that the statement <em>“you don’t need to be a developer to contribute to open source, you can also report bugs”</em> is not entirely true. The unnecessary noise taht is made by such behavior hinders the developer, which is doing that voluntary.</p>
<p>Windows has no exclusive unpopularity. There are enough people that are complaining about PulseAudio, Systemd, Electron, PHP and others. But the most of them don&rsquo;t deserve that, and so doesn&rsquo;t Windows.</p>
<p>I hope you can understand my point of view on this topic. If you have questions, feel free to <a href="https://ninelore.github.io/#about-me">contact me</a></p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Welcome to ninelore's Blog</title><link>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/001-my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 19:37:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ninelore.github.io/posts/001-my-first-post/</guid><description>Welcome to my new Blog I decided to make this Blog to write about my thoughs, how random they may be. Possible Topics could be:
experience i made opinions i need to share tutorials whatever else could come in my mind Why i decided to start a Blog It was the recent Post of the Lutris founder Mathieu that ignited an uge inside me that i should share my thoughs. I dont really know what anything else to say besides that.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcome-to-my-new-blog">Welcome to my new Blog</h1>
<p>I decided to make this Blog to write about my thoughs, how random they may be. Possible Topics could be:</p>
<ul>
<li>experience i made</li>
<li>opinions i need to share</li>
<li>tutorials</li>
<li>whatever else could come in my mind</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="why-i-decided-to-start-a-blog">Why i decided to start a Blog</h2>
<p>It was the recent <a href="http://mathieu.comandon.org/not-on-the-same-page">Post of the Lutris founder Mathieu</a> that ignited an uge inside me that i should share my thoughs. I dont really know what anything else to say besides that.</p>
<p>I hope that you will like my content ;)</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>